Now, let's see how to convert this raw calculation into a standardized factor.
下面看看如何将这个原始计算值变成标准化因子
We want the resulting weights to satisfy two conditions.
我们希望权重满足两个条件
First, we want the sum of the weights to add up to zero.
首先 我们希望权重之和为 0
Second, we want the absolute values of the weights to sum to one.
其次 我们希望权重的绝对值和为 1
To satisfy the first condition,
为了满足第一个条件
we want to find the mean or average of the list of raw factor values for all the stocks.
我们要计算所有股票的原始因子值的均值
Then, subtract that mean from each of the raw factor values.
然后用每个原始因子值减去均值
We say that we de-mean the factor,
也就是对因子去均值
because we're subtracting it's mean.
因为减去均值
To satisfy the second condition,
为了满足第二个条件
we want to re-scale the values.
我们需要重新调整这些值
To re-scale, we divide each value by a number.
即让每个值除以一个数字
This scalar, equals the sum of the absolute values.
这个度量范围等于绝对值的和
So, we re-scale the values by dividing each value by this scalar.
我们让每个值都除以这个度量范围
To standardize a vector of factor values,
为了标准化因子值向量
we both de-mean and re-scale,
我们通过去均值和重新调整范围
so that the mean of this two list of numbers equals zero,
使这个列表中的数字均值等于 0
and the sum of the absolute values equals one.
并且绝对值之和等于 1
We could do the de-mean or re-scale,
去均值和重新调整范围的
one after the other in either order.
执行顺序不重要
Let's walk through an example with three stocks,
以有三支股票的投资组合为例
each with a factor value such as a one year return.
每个都包含表示年度收益率的因子值
First, we want to de-mean the values so that they sum to zero.
首先去均值 使它们的和等于 0
So, we calculate the mean by adding up the values of A,
将 A B 和 C 的值相加
B, and C, then divide by the number of stocks.
然后除以股票数量
Then, for each stock,
对于每支股票
we get the raw factor value minus the mean.
用原始因子值减去均值
Next, we want to re-scale so that the sum of absolute values equals one.
下一步重新调整范围 使绝对值之和等于 1
We can get the scalar by adding up the absolute values of the numbers.
将数字的绝对值相加 得出度量范围
To re-scale, we divide each value by the scalar.
为了重新调整范围 我们将每个值除以该度量范围
This gives us the standardized values for the factor.
得出因子的标准化值
We can verify the conditions that the sum is equal to
检验下和是否等于 0
zero and the sum of the absolute values equals one.
以及绝对值之和是否等于 1
Feel free to pause the video,
如果你想仔细研究下这些步骤
if you want to study these steps in detail.
可以暂停视频 好好研究下
Great. So, now you know how de-meaning and re-scaling
好的现在你知道去均值和重新调整范围
can convert raw calculations into candidates for alpha factors.
可以将原始计算值变成候选 alpha 因子
This is actually how we standardize factors so that we can
我们就是通过这种方式标准化因子
evaluate them and compare them with other factors.
从而将它们与其他因子进行比较
Next, we'll look at how to interpret,
下一步我们将解释
why we take these steps to standardize a factor.
为何要标准化因子
But first, here's a random question to ponder,
先思考一个问题
why were the normal distribution and the raw factor both
为何正态分布和原始因子
very unhappy when they were told that they would be standardized?
听到标准化流程时不开心？
One, I know the answer, because they thought it was de-meaning.
因为它们以为是降低身份
Get it? De-meaning.
听懂了吗？降低身份